trustyou.com 2019-04-30

# Privacy Statement

                                    Privacy Statement
                                        TrustYou GmbH
This is the privacy statement of TrustYou GmbH, Steinerstraße 15, 81369 Munich, (hereinafter
referred to as “TrustYou“ or “we“).
The protection of your data is our main concern
We appreciate your interest in our company, our products and services, and we want you to feel
safe in terms of personal data protection whenever you visit our Internet pages. We take the
protection of your personal data very seriously. Consequently, we comply with all the relevant
data protection regulations and constantly strive to optimize our data protection processes.
We would like you to be informed on what data we collect, when we collect them, what type of
data we collect, to what purposes and how we use them. We have taken the technical and
organizational measures that are meant to secure the observance of the regulations on the
protection of personal data both by us and by our external service providers.
This Privacy Statement informs you on the processing of your personal data by TrustYou outside
and in connection to the website www.trustyou.com.
                                                                           November, 2018      1

Contents
1. Person in charge                                                              3
2. Personal Data                                                                 3
3. Website operation                                                             3
4. Processed data                                                                3
       4.1. Automatically collected data                                         3
       4.2. Data provided                                                        4
5. Data processing purposes                                                      4
       5.1. User account for TrustYou products                                   4
       5.2. Contact via the contact form and e-mail                              5
       5.3. E-mail newsletters & further e-mail campaigns                        6
       5.4. Entering into agreements6                                            6
       5.5. Applicant data                                                       6
       5.6. Data transfer                                                        7
6. Tracking tools for website analysis 6.1. General information7                 7
       6.2. Google Analytics                                                     8
       6.3. Google Adwords / Remarketing                                        10
       6.4. Google Adwords / Conversion Tracking                                10
       6.5. Google Tag Manager                                                  11
       6.6. Doubleclick by Google                                               11
       6.7. Marketo Munchkin                                                    12
7. Use of external service providers 12                                         13
8. Storage period                                                               13
9. Your rights                                                                  13
10. Inquiries                                                                   12
                                                                 November, 2018   2

1. Person in charge
   The person in charge of the processing of your personal data is TrustYou GmbH,
   Steinerstraße 15, 81369 Munich. For further information see our imprint on trustyou.com.
2. Personal Data
   Personal data represent information concerning an identified or identifiable natural person,
   such as your name, e-mail address, phone number, address or the IP address of your
   computer.
3. Website operation
   We process your personal data in order to be able to provide you with the best possible
   customized offers and information and to make your visit on our website as insightful and
   gainful as possible. Unless otherwise set forth in the following provisions, the legal basis
   for such data processing is, in each case, Article 6(1)(f) GDPR (Legitimate interests, based
   on our interest to offer you the best possible attractive website).
4. Processed data
   4.1.    Automatically collected data
          In order to be able to display the most suitable information for you, we process the
          following data:
               ●      Address of the page you have visited on our website
               ●      Address of the website you have visited immediately before our website
                      (the so-called “Referrer”)
               ●      Date and time of your visit
               ●      Features of your terminal, particularly the operating system, the browser
                      used and the window size of your browser
               ●      IP address of your terminal in the Internet
                                                                          November, 2018        3

              ●      Identification numbers that we store on your terminal. These identification
                     numbers help us recognize your terminal on the website. Technically
                     speaking, these identification numbers are stored in the so-called cookies
                     or eTags.
              ●      Device identifiers consisting of individual features of your terminal. These
                     device identifiers also help us recognize your terminal on the website.
                     Example of such device identifiers are:
                    o   “Ad-ID“ of the Apple operating system iOS
                    o   “Ad-ID“ of the Android operating system
         The legal basis for such data processing is Article 6(1)(f) GDPR (Legitimate
         interests, based on our interest to provide you with a trouble-free website optimized
         for your terminal).
   4.2.  Data provided
         Additionally, we process your personal data when, due to your interest in our
         products, you contact us via our website or otherwise and/or when you conclude
         agreements with us for the purchase of our products. Unless otherwise set forth in
         the following provisions, the legal basis for such data processing is, in each case,
         Article 6(1)(b) GDPR (Performance of contract).
5. Data processing purposes
   5.1.  User account for TrustYou products
         In order to be able to receive our products, you must first register with us. You can
         do this in a comfortable and easy manner through our registration form under
         www.trustyou.com/contact-us?lang=de. Following the registration and the
         successful login, various information, services and products are made available to
         you. For the creation of the user account we require your first and last name, your
         e-mail address, as well as your phone number. Moreover, the users must provide
         the name of the company, payment details, as well as information regarding the
         registered office of the company.
                                                                         November, 2018          4

     You can, of course, terminate the agreement for the user account at any time and
     without giving reasons. The easiest way to do this is to send an informal e-mail to
     service@trustyou.com.
     The legal basis for such data processing is, in each case, Article 6(1)(b) GDPR
     (Performance of contract for the provision of the user account) and Article 6(1)(f)
     GDPR (Legitimate interests, based on our interest to offer you information, services
     and products), respectively.
                •   Address of the page you have visited on our website
                •   Address of the website you have visited immediately before our
                    website (the so-called “Referrer”)
                •   Date and time of your visit
                •   Features of your terminal, particularly the operating system, the
                    browser used and the window size of your browser
                •   IP address of your terminal in the Internet
                •   Identification numbers that we store on your terminal. These
                    identification numbers help us recognize your terminal on the website.
                    Technically speaking, these identification numbers are stored in the so-
                    called cookies or eTags.
                •   Device identifiers consisting of individual features of your terminal.
                    These device identifiers also help us recognize your terminal on the
                    website. Example of such device identifiers are:
                        o   “Ad-ID“ of the Apple operating system iOS
                        o   “Ad-ID“ of the Android operating system
5.2. Contact via the contact form and e-mail
     If you send us inquiries via the contact form or e-mail, we process the information
     provided therein, including the contact details you have provided for the processing
     of the inquiry.
     Such data are also stored with us for possible further inquiries. The legal basis for
     this is Article 6(1)(b) GDPR (Performance of contract - the processing of the user’s
     data is necessary for the performance of the contract regarding the reply to inquiries
                                                                      November, 2018       5

        and/or concerns) and Article 6(1)(f) GDPR (Legitimate interests - based on our
        interest to process inquiries of our website’s users).
5.3.    E-mail newsletters & further e-mail campaigns
        We provide all our website users and/or customers and interested parties with an e-
        mail newsletter and/or further e-mail campaigns. In order to subscribe, the user can
        register for the web offer with his/her e-mail address. Subsequently, the user
        receives an activation link at the provided e-mail address, a link that the user must
        click on, in order to complete the subscription. This way, the user consents to the
        receipt of an e-mail newsletter and/or further e-mail campaigns (double-opt-in
        procedure).
        The consent to receive the e-mail newsletter and/or further e-mail campaigns can
        be revoked at any time, without giving reasons. The easiest way to do this is to click
        on the “Unsubscribe” link, which can be found in every e-mail. The legal basis for
        such data processing is Article 6(1)(a) GDPR in conjunction with your consent.
   5.4. Entering into agreements
        Insofar as we enter into agreements with our customers and service providers, for
        service provision purposes, we process the personal data of the persons authorized
        to sign the agreements and of the customers’ and service providers’ contact persons.
        The legal basis for such data processing is Article 6(1)(b) GDPR (Performance of
        contract) and Article 6(1)(f) GDPR (Legitimate interests, based on our interest to
        provide our customers and service providers with relevant information).
   5.5. Applicant data
        Applicants are given the possibility to apply for advertised jobs via our website or
        Linkedin. In this respect, we process the applicants’ personal data (first and last
        name, e-mail address, phone number, curriculum vitae (CV), cover letter, salary
        expectations, availability, previous employer, possibly certificates,
        recommendations, etc.) exclusively in order to decide on the establishment of an
        employment relationship, and, if so, in order to perform and terminate such a
        relationship. The legal basis for such data processing is Article 88 GDPR in
        conjunction with Article 26(1) BDSG (German Federal Data Protection Act).
                                                                       November, 2018         6

       We erase the applicant’s data within 6 months the latest as it becomes obvious that
       no employment relationship is justified. This does not apply if the applicant has
       consented that we store the data for a longer period and in order to receive other
       job offers from TrustYou during this period, if necessary. The applicant can revoke
       such consent at any time, by means of an informal e-mail to hr@trustyou.com. In
       this case, the data are immediately erased.
5.6.   Data transfer
       Your personal data will only be transferred to third parties by us if this is necessary
       to fulfil the contract, if we or the third party have a legitimate interest in the transfer
       or if you have consented to the transfer. If data is transferred to third parties on the
       basis of a legitimate interest, this is explained in these data protection provisions.
       In addition, personal data may be transferred to third parties insofar as we are
       obliged to do so by law or by enforceable official or court order.
       If we disclose personal data to third parties or contract processors based in non-
       EEA countries, we will ensure that the recipient either has an adequate level of data
       protection (e.g. based on an EU Commission adequacy decision for the country in
       question, a self-certification of the recipient for the EU Privacy Shield or the
       agreement of so-called EU standard contractual clauses of the European Union with
       the recipient) or has obtained sufficient consent from our users prior to disclosure.
    6.  Tracking tools for website analysis
6.1.   General information
       We want to design our web pages as optimal as possible. Therefore, we use so-
       called tracking tools in order to technically improve our web offers. The tracking
       tools allow us to measure the usage of our web offers. With the help of the tracking
       tools we collect the following information, in particular:
          •  The links on which the online users click on other websites, in order to reach
             www.trustyou.com.
                                                                         November, 2018            7

       • Which of our pages are searched for, when, how often and in which sequence?
       • What is the information that the users of our website search for?
       • What links and/or offers do the users of our website click on?
     Based on such information we prepare statistics that help us understand the
     following questions:
       • Which pages are particularly attractive to the users of our website?
       • Which articles are our users interested in, the most?
       • Which offers should we make to our users?
     For these purposes, we mainly use the automatically collected data listed under
     Section 4.1. The data are stored only under a pseudonym. The legal basis for this is
     your consent within the meaning of Article 6(1)(a) GDPR, as well as Article 6(1)(f)
     GDPR (Legitimate interests, based on our interest to adapt the website to our users’
     interests and needs, to the best possible extent).
6.2. Google Analytics
     This website uses Google Analytics, a web analysis service of Google Inc.
     ("Google"). Google Analytics uses the so-called “cookies”, text files that are stored
     on your computer and enable an analysis of the website usage through you. The
     information generated by the cookies regarding your use of this website is usually
     transferred and stored on a server of Google in the USA. If the IP anonymisation is
     activated on this website, Google will condense your IP address beforehand, within
     the member states of the European Union or other States party to the Agreement
     on the European Economic Area. The whole IP address is transferred and stored on
     a server of Google in the USA only in exceptional cases. On behalf of the operator
     of this website, Google uses such information in order to assess your use of the
     website, to prepare reports on the website activity and to provide the website
     operator with further services related to the website and Internet usage.
     The IP address communicated by your browser within the framework of Google
     Analytics is not merged with other data of Google.
     You can prevent the storage of the cookies through a corresponding setting of your
     browser software; however, please note that, in this case, you might not be able to
                                                                   November, 2018          8

use all the functions of this website to a full extent. Additionally, you can prevent the
recording with Google of the data generated through the cookie and related to your
use of the website (including the IP address), as well as the processing of such data
by Google, by downloading and installing the browser plugin available under the
following link: tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=de.
This website used Google Analytics with the extension "_anonymizeIp()". This way,
the IP addresses are further processed in their condensed form, thus ruling out a
possible identification of the user. If the data collected about you imply any person-
related references, such data are immediately excluded and the personal data are
promptly erased.
We use Google Analytics in order to be able to analyze and to constantly improve
the use of our website. The obtained statistics help us improve our offer and make it
more interesting for you as a user. For the exceptional cases in which personal data
are transferred in the USA, Google has adhered to the EU-US Privacy Shield,
www.privacy-shield.gov/EU-US-Framework. The processing of your data within the
framework of Google Analytics occurs for the safeguarding of the legitimate
interests of Intervox.
Information to third-party providers: Google Dublin, Google Ireland Ltd., Gordon
House, Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Ireland, Fax: +353 (1) 436 1001. User conditions:
www.google.com/analytics/terms/de.html, Data protection overview:
www.google.com/intl/de/analytics/learn/privacy.html, as well as the privacy
statement: www.google.de/intl/de/policies/privacy.
Objection to data recording
You can prevent the recording with and transfer to Google of the data related to
your use of the website (including the IP address), as well as the processing of such
data by Google, by downloading and installing the browser plugin available under
the following link: tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=de.
                                                                 November, 2018          9

6.3.  Google Adwords / Remarketing
     Additionally, we use the remarketing function in Google AdWords of Google Inc.,
      1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA (hereinafter referred
      to as “Google“). The Remarketing feature allows TrustYou to present the website
      users with advertisements of other websites within the Google Ad Network (i.e., on
      Google itself, the so-called "Google Ads" or other websites), based on their
      interests. For this, the application analyzes our users’ interaction with our website,
      focusing on the offers that the users have shown interest in, so as to be able to
      display targeted advertisements for them on other websites that the users visit
      subsequently. In doing so, Google saves cookies in the browsers of the users who
      visit certain Google services or websites within the Google display network. This
      cookie records the user’s visits. This number serves the clear identification of a web
      browser on a certain computer and not the identification of a person, and thus no
      personal data are stored. The user may prevent the cookie by means of a setting in
      his/her browser software. Additionally, the user can disable the use of cookies by
      Google, by following the link
     www.google.com/settings/ads/plugin and installing the plug-in provided there.
      Further information regarding Google Adwords, as well as the Privacy Statement of
      Google can be viewed under: www.google.com/privacy/ads.
     Commissioned data processing
     We have concluded a commissioned data processing agreement with Google,
      endorsed by the German data protection authorities.
6.4.  Google Adwords / Conversion Tracking
     Additionally, we also use the Conversion Tracking of Google AdWords of Google
      Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA (hereinafter
      referred to as “Google“). When you click on a Google ad, a Conversion Tracking
      cookie is set on your computer. These cookies expire after 30 days, collect no
      personal data and therefore do not serve the personal identification. When you visit
      certain Internet pages of our website and the cookie has not expired, yet, Google
      and we can know that you have clicked on the ad and have been redirected to this
                                                                     November, 2018          10

      page. Each Google AdWords client receives another cookie. This way, the cookies
      cannot be tracked across the websites of AdWords clients. The information
      gathered with the help of the Conversion cookies is used to prepare conversion
      statistics for the Adwords clients that have opted for Conversion Tracking. The
      Adwords clients find out the total number of users that have clicked on their ad and
      have been redirected to a page provided with a conversion tracking tag. However,
      they do not receive any information capable of personally identifying the users. The
      user may prevent the cookie by means of a setting in his/her browser software.
      Additionally, the user can disable the use of cookies by Google, by following the link
      www.google.com/settings/ads/plugin and installing the plug-in provided there.
      Further information regarding Google Adwords, as well as the Privacy Statement of
      Google can be viewed under: www.google.com/privacy/ads.
     Commissioned data processing
     We have concluded a commissioned data processing agreement with Google,
     endorsed by the German data protection authorities.
6.5. Google Tag Manager
     For transparency reasons, we point out that we use the Google Tag Manager. The
     Google Tag Manager does not collect any personal data. The Tag Manager
     facilitates the integration and management of our tags. Tags are small code
     elements that serve, among other things, the measurement of traffic and visitor
     behavior, the determination of the effect of online advertising and social media, the
     remarketing and setting up of target groups and the testing and optimization of
     websites. We use the Tag Manager for the Google services Google Analytics and
     GA Audience. If you have chosen a deactivation, such deactivation is considered by
     the Google Tag Manager. For further information regarding the Google Tag Manager
     see: www.google.com/intl/de/tagmanager/use-policy.html.
6.6. Doubleclick by Google
     We also use the Doubleclick by Google. Doubleclick by Google is a service provided
     by Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA
     (“Google“). With Doubleclick by Google we display ads that are relevant to you. You
                                                                   November, 2018          11

     see these ads on our website and on the websites of other providers that also work
     together with Google. In your browser for Google, our website saves a so-called
     “cookie” with a pseudonym identification number (ID). With the help of the cookie ID,
     Google recognizes your browser when you visit our website (or other websites, the
     providers of which also use the Doubleclick by Google). This way, Google tries to
     gather the following information:
         •  Which web pages have you visited?
         •  Which ads of Google have been displayed to you during the visit?
         •  Which of these ads have you clicked on?
     Based on such information, Google selects the ads that you will be displayed by
     Google. You can manage the display of such ads by Google here
     (www.google.com/settings/ads) . You can find further information regarding the
     advertising through Google here (www.google.com/policies/technologies/ads). You
     can find further information on data protection with Google here
     (www.google.com/intl/de/policies/privacy).
     Google operates its servers in the USA, i.e. in a third country outside the EU. The
     DoubleClick service of Google transfers your data to these servers. There is
     currently no decision of the EU Commission that the USA generally provides an
     adequate level of protection. However, Google has adhered to the “EU-U.S. Privacy
     Shield Framework” which provides adequate and proper guarantees. You can find
     further information in this respect here (www.privacyshield.gov/welcome).
     The legal basis for the integration of Doubleclick by Google, as described in this
     section, is Article 6(1)(f) GDPR (Legitimate interests, based on our interest to market
     the website for advertising purposes). Google collects and processes the data
     accrued within such framework under its own responsibility.
6.7. Marketo Munchkin
     This cookie is set by Marketo. It enables a website to track the visitors’ behavior on
     the websites on which the cookie is installed, and to link a visitor with the recipient
     of an e-mail marketing campaign, in order to measure the efficiency of the
     campaign. The referrer (if any), the current URL and, if applicable, the destination
     URL is sent for each activity. The tracking occurs anonymously until a user
                                                                    November, 2018           12

       identifies him/herself by submitting a form. The legal basis for the integration of
       Marketo Munchkin, as described in this section, is Article 6(1)(f) GDPR (Legitimate
       interests, based on our interest to determine the efficiency of marketing
       campaigns).
7.     Use of external service providers
For the operation of our website, we entrust external service providers with the processing
of data (e.g. for the storage of data in data centers). If necessary, such service providers
process personal data, as well. We select and monitor the service providers carefully. They
process the data exclusively according to our instructions, based on proper agreements for
commissioned data processing.
8.     Storage period
We keep personal data only as long as this is necessary for the fulfillment of the purposes
herein and/or for the retention periods stipulated by law. The data that you provide within
the meaning of Section 4.2 are therefore erased not later than the expiry of the possible
commercial and fiscal retention periods, after 6 years. Automatically collected data within
the meaning of Section 4.1 are erased or anonymized after 14 months, at the latest.
9.     Your rights
You have the following rights with regard to your personal data:
    o  Right to access personal data
    o  Right to object
    o  Right to rectification or erasure
    o  Right to restriction of processing
    o  Right to data portability
Please use the information under Contact to assert your rights. Please make sure that we
can uniquely identify you.
You can also object to the processing of your personal data for advertising purposes at any
time ("Advertising Objection"). Please note that for organisational reasons there may be an
                                                                       November, 2018        13

 overlap between your revocation and the use of your data within the framework of an
 ongoing campaign.
 You also have the right to file a complaint with a data protection authority. You can contact
 the data protection authority responsible for your place of residence or federal state or the
 data protection authority responsible for us. This is:
        Bavarian State Office for Data Protection Supervision (BayLDA)
        Promenade 27
        D-91522 Ansbach, Germany
        poststelle@lda.bayern.de
10.     Inquiries
 For general inquiries or suggestions with regard to data protection please do not hesitate to
 contact our data protection officer directly:
        TrustYou Datenschutzbeauftragter
        Steinerstraße 15
        81369 München
        E-Mail: dataprotection@trustyou.com
                                                                      November, 2018           14
